很久很久以前，在一个遥远的银河中...
星 球
大 战
西斯的复仇
第三章
战争！共和国在无情的西斯尊王和杜库伯爵的攻击下逐渐粉碎
两边都有强大的英雄  然而到处都充斥着邪恶
在迅猛的攻势下  邪恶的帝国军首领格里弗斯将军
攻入了共和国首都...
绑架了银河议会的领导帕尔帕廷议长
正当分裂主义者帝国军
尝试挟持他们手中宝贵的人质
从被包围的首都里逃脱时
两名绝地武士拼死展开了拯救议长的任务...
锁定他  R2
Lock on to him, R2.
师傅  格里弗斯将军的旗舰就在正前方
Master, General Grievous's ship is directly ahead...
与秃鹫机器人一起缓慢前进的那艘
the one crawling with vulture droids.
噢  我看到了  这下好办多了
I see it. Oh, this is going to be easy.
- “老怪”  收到吗? - 收到  红色领队
- "Oddball", do you copy? - Copy, Red Leader.
标记我的位置  带你的中队跟在我后上方
Mark my position. Form your squad up behind me.
我们在您后面了  克诺比将军
We're on your tail, General Kenobi.
展开S翼  进入攻击位置
Set S-foils in attack position.
好戏要开始了
This is where the fun begins.
让他们从我们中间穿过
Let them pass between us.
我被盯上了
They're all over me.
- 快帮我...    - 我过去支援他们
- Get them off my... - I'm gonna go help them out.
不要  他们干他们的任务  我们干我们的
No. They are doing their job so we can do ours.
导弹  爬升
Missiles. Pull up.
- 没打中我们 - 又绕回来了
- They overshot us. - They're coming around.
没事的  R4 不要这样  别玩高难度动作
All right, R4. No, no. Nothing too fancy.
释放所有能量  R2  准备倒转推进器
Surge all power units, R2. Stand by reverse thrusters.
搞定了  R2
We got 'em, R2.
飞行真不是人干的
Flying is for droids.
- 我被击中了  阿纳金?  - 看到了
- I'm hit. Anakin?   - I see them.
是蜂鸣机器人
Buzz droids.
R4  小心  你那边有一个...
R4, be careful. You have a...
噢  天啊
Oh, dear.
他们正试图关闭所有控制开关
They're shutting down all the controls.
往右边移一点  我帮你打掉他们
Move to the right so I can get a clear shot at them.
记得你的任务 去指挥船里
The mission. Get to the command ship.
去营救议长  我这里已经没救了
Get the chancellor. I'm running out of tricks here.
噢  上帝啊...
In the name of...
- 别开火了!  这么做没用的   - 我也同意  真不是个好主意
- Hold your fire! You're not helping. - I agree. Bad idea.
我什么都看不到了  座舱里都是烟
I can't see a thing. My cockpit's fogging.
我被他们包围了  阿纳金!
They're all over me. Anakin!
- 靠右一点 - 等等  这样我们俩都会没命的
- Move to the right. - Hold on. You'll get us both killed.
快离开这里  你在这里也没有用
Get out of here. There's nothing more you can do.
师傅  我不会离开你的
I'm not leaving without you, Master.
搞定他  R2
Get him, R2.
当心
Watch out.
R2  射它中间的眼睛
R2, hit the buzz droid's centre eye.
- 太好了  你搞定它了！ - 干得好  R2
- Yeah, you got him! - Great, R2.
格里弗斯将军的旗船就在前面了
The general's command ship is dead ahead.
你没注意到保护罩还开着吗？
Have you noticed the shields are still up?
不好意思  师傅
Sorry, Master.
我有种不祥的预感
I have a bad feeling about this.
在那儿  抓住他们
There they are. Get them.
R2  找出议长在哪里
R2, locate the chancellor.
议长的信号好象是从那里发出来的
The chancellor's signal is coming from right there...
尖顶上那个观察平台
the observation platform at the top of that spire.
我感觉到杜库伯爵了
I sense Count Dooku.
- 我感觉到了圈套 - 下一步?
- I sense a trap. - Next move?
跳出这个圈套
Spring the trap.
R2  回去  我要你呆在船上
R2, go back. I need you to stay with the ship.
拿着这个  等我们的命令
Here. Take this and wait for orders.
舰长  现在情况怎么样
What's the situation, Captain?
两个绝地武士在机库着陆了  我们正在跟踪他们
Two Jedi have landed in the main hangar bay. We're tracking them.
真让杜库伯爵说对了
Just as Count Dooku predicted.
毁灭者
Destroyers.
放下武器  我叫你们放下武器
Drop your weapons. I said drop 'em.
- 明白 - 明白  明白
- Roger. - Roger, roger.
那些就是绝地武士的战机吧
Those are Jedi fighters all right.
- 你按停了? - 没有啊  你呢?
- Did you press the stop button? - No. Did you?
还有别的路可以出去
There's more than one way out of here.
我们不是要出去 让电梯动起来
We don't want to get out. We want to get moving.
R2  激活31174号电梯
R2, activate elevator 31174.
- 听到么  R2 - 什么声音?
- Come in, R2. - What that?
R2  收到没?
R2, do you copy?
R2  激活电梯31174
R2, activate the elevator number 31174.
回去干活吧  没事
Get back to work. That nothin'.
激活31174号电梯
Activate the elevator 31174.
R2  我们...
R2...
总是那么冲动
Always on the move.
R2  接通连线 R2  能听到么?
R2, switch on the comlink. R2, can you hear me?
R2?
R2！  R2！
R2! R2!
停下  我们要往上走
Stop. Stop. R2, we need to be going up.
绝地武士  举起手来
Hands up,Jedi.
R2  你收到没有?
R2, do you copy?
R2  听到没有  我们要上  不是下
R2, do you hear me? R2, we need to be going up, not down.
嘿  你！
Hey, you!
对  这样子就对了
That's better.
你这个愚蠢的机器人
You stupid little astro droid.
噢  是你啊
Oh, it's you.
我的眼睛！  我的眼睛！
My eyes! My eyes!
- 刚刚怎么回事啊? - R2他...
- What was that all about? - R2 has been...
- 不是他的错 - 我说什么了吗?
- No loose wire jokes. - Did I say anything?
- 他已经在努力了   - 噢  我可什么都没说
- He's trying. - I didn't say anything.
- 议长 - 你还好吗?
- Chancellor. - Are you all right?
杜库伯爵
Count Dooku.
- 这次我们一起上 - 我正想这么说
- This time we will do it together. - I was about to say that.
找支援吧  你们不是他的对手  他是西斯尊主
Get help. You're no match for him. He's a Sith lord.
帕尔帕廷议长  我们最擅长就是对付西斯尊主
Chancellor Palpatine, Sith lords are our speciality.
亮出你们的剑吧
Your swords, please.
在议长面前我们可不想打得太难看
We don't want to make a mess of things in front of the chancellor.
你这次别想逃了  杜库
You won't get away this time, Dooku.
我也等了很久了
I've been looking forward to this.
伯爵  我的力量比上次见面提升了一倍
My powers have doubled since the last time we met, Count.
很好  信心翻倍  失败也翻倍
Good. Twice the pride, double the fall.
好
Get...
我感觉得到你的恐惧  天行者
I sense great fear in you, Skywalker.
你憎恨  你愤怒
You have hate. You have anger.
但是你没有好好利用它们
But you don't use them.
干得好  阿纳金
Good, Anakin. Good.
杀了他
Kill him.
现在就杀了他
Kill him now.
我不可以
I shouldn't.
动手
Do it.
你干得太棒了  阿纳金
You did well, Anakin.
把他留在世上太危险了
He was too dangerous to be kept alive.
是的  但是他已经是阶下囚了
Yes, but he was an unarmed prisoner.
我不该那么做的  绝地武士不该那样
I shouldn't have done that. It's not the Jedi way.
这很平常的  他斩了你的手臂  你杀了他报仇
It is only natural. He cut off your arm, and you wanted revenge.
这不是第一次了  阿纳金
It wasn't the first time, Anakin.
还记得你告诉我关于你母亲和沙地人的事吗
Remember what you told me about your mother and the Sand People?
在更多保安机器人来之前  我们得走了
Now we must leave before more security droids arrive.
阿纳金  没有时间了
Anakin, there's no time.
我们要马上离开这艘船
We must get off this ship before it's too late.
- 他只是晕过去了 - 别管他了  不然我们就赶不及了
- He seems to be all right. - Leave him, or we'll never make it.
我不会丢下他不管的
His fate will be the same as ours.
准备舷侧炮击！
Prepare for attack!
全力开火！  开火！
All batteries, fire! Fire!
电梯失灵了
Elevator's not working.
R2  激活3224号电梯
R2, activate elevator 3224.
- 倒转稳定器   - 倒转稳定器
- Reverse stabilizers. - Reversing stabilizers.
开动磁场！  开动磁场！
Magnetize! Magnetize!
启动紧急助推引擎
Fire the emergency booster engines.
水平恢复中  长官
We're levelling out, sir.
放松  我们只是有点小麻烦
Easy. We're in a bit of a situation here.
- 发生什么了? - 抓住
- Did I miss something? - Hold on.
- 那是什么? - 噢老天
- What is that? - Oops.
R2  R2  把电梯停下来
R2. R2, shut down the elevator.
太晚了  跳！
Too late. Jump!
看看机库里还有没有可以飞的东西
Let's see if we can find something in the hangar bay that's still flyable.
R2  下来
R2, get down here.
R2  收到没?
R2, do you copy?
将军  找到绝地武士了 他们在328号走廊
General, we found the Jedi. They're in hallway 328.
启动射线罩
Activate ray shields.
射线罩
Ray shields.
等等  怎么会这样? 不该发生这种事情的
Wait a minute. How did this happen? We're smarter than this.
显然不是
Apparently not.
- 我说耐心些 - 耐心?
- I say patience. - Patience?
是的  R2很快就会过来
Yes. R2 will be along in a few moments...
然后解除射线罩的
and then he'll release the ray shields.
看吧  没问题的
See? No problem.
别动
Don't move.
你还有后备方案吗?
Do you have a plan B?
来了
Ah, yes.
谈判代表
The negotiator.
克诺比将军  我们等了你很久了
General Kenobi. We've been waiting for you.
抱歉
Excuse me.
- 这真不像是拯救行动 - 不客气
- That wasn't much of a rescue. - You're welcome.
还有...
And...
阿纳金.天行者
Anakin Skywalker.
名头那么响  没想到你这么年轻
I was expecting someone with your reputation to be a little... older.
格里弗斯将军  我也以为你会高一点的
General Grievous. You're shorter than I expected.
绝地垃圾
Jedi scum.
我们还有事要做  阿纳金  别惹他
We have a job to do, Anakin. Try not to upset him.
你们的激光剑会成为我的又一件收藏品
Your lightsabres will make a fine addition to my collection.
这可不行  而且这次你也别想逃
Not this time. And this time, you won't escape.
R2
R2.
干掉他们！
Crush them!
尝尝我们的厉害！
Make them suffer!
来吧，现在！
Come. Now!
坚守你们的岗位！
Stay at your stations!
干掉他！ 干掉他！
Get him! Get him!
快跑！
Run!
别理他们
Don't bother with them.
- 保持行驶轨道 - 遵命
- Keep the ship in orbit. - Yes, sir.
你输了  克诺比将军
You lose, General Kenobi.
快离开这里！  快跑！
Get out of here! Run!
是时候弃船了
Time to abandon ship.
所有救生船都发射走了
All the escape pods have been launched.
是格里弗斯干的  你开得了这种巡洋舰嘛?
Grievous. Can you fly a cruiser like this?
- 你是指我能不能把这堆废铁弄到地面上去吧? - 嗯?
- You mean, can I land what's left of it? - Well?
这种情况下
Under the circumstances,
飞行技术跟能不能降落都没有关系了
I'd say the ability to pilot this thing is irrelevant.
系好安全带
Strap yourselves in.
打开所有舱盖  辅翼  张开缓冲片甲
Open all hatches. Extend all flaps and drag fins.
我们好象掉了什么
We lost something.
别担心  我们还有半条船
Not to worry. We are still flying half a ship.
我想我们开太快了
Now we're really picking up speed.
8加60
Eight plus 60.
- 我们进入大气层了 - 抓着那个  保持水平
- We're in the atmosphere. - Grab that. Keep us level.
稳住
Steady.
放轻松  R2
Easy, R2.
5000.
救火船在左右就位
Fire ships on the left and the right.
- 我们领你们降落 - 收到
- We'll take you in. - Copy that.
- 跑道就在前面了 - 我们的机身太热了
- Landing strip, straight ahead. - We're coming in too hot.
又一次愉快的着陆
Another happy landing.
你不来吗  师傅?
Coming, Master?
不  我不太想看到那些政客
No. I'm not brave enough for politics.
我要到委员会去汇报这次的行动
I have to report to the council.
而且  有人更适合做英雄
Besides, someone needs to be the poster boy.
等等  整个行动都是你策划的
Hold on. This whole operation was your idea.
别忘了是你把我从蜂式机器人中救出来的  阿纳金
Let us not forget, Anakin, that you rescued me from the buzz droids.
是你杀了杜库  救了议长
And you killed Count Dooku, and you rescued the chancellor...
然后把晕倒的我背出来的
carrying me unconscious on your back.
都是你教我的  师傅
All because of your training.
阿纳金  公平一点  今天  你就是英雄
Anakin, let's be fair. Today you were the hero...
你应当得到政客们的嘉勉
and you deserve your glorious day with the politicians.
好吧  不过除了这第10次救你之外  你还欠我一份情
All right. But you owe me one, and not for saving your skin for the 1Oth time.
是第9次
Ninth time.
凯特坑道那次不算 例会上见
That business on Cato Neimoidia doesn't count. I'll see you at the briefing.
帕尔帕廷议长  你还好吗?
Chancellor Palpatine, are you all right?
是的  多亏了两位绝地武士
Yes. Thanks to your two Jedi knights.
他们杀了杜库伯爵  但是又被格里弗斯将军逃脱了
They killed Count Dooku, but General Grievous has escaped once again.
格里弗斯向来就只会干这种事  他是个懦夫
General Grievous will run and hide, as he always does. He's a coward.
杜库死后  他就是帝国军的头领了
But with Count Dooku dead, he is the leader of the droid army.
我可以保证地说...
And I assure you...
议会都会继续支持这场战役
the senate will vote to continue the war
只要格里弗斯一天不死
as long as Grievous is alive.
那么绝地委员会也将把寻找格里弗斯作为首要任务
Then the Jedi Council will make finding Grievous our highest priority.
- 当心 - 抱歉
- Watch it. - Excuse me.
- 过来  R2 - 共和国真是多亏你了
- Come along, R2. - The Republic cannot praise you enough.
谢谢夸奖  奥加纳议员
Thank you, Senator Organa.
等等  情况不可能有那么差吧
It couldn't possibly be as bad as all that.
对  我也同意这一点
Now there I agree with you.
事实上  我调校一下也可以做到你那样的
In fact, I could do with a tune-up myself.
不过在格里弗斯没死之前  战争还得继续
But the fighting will continue until General Grievous is spare parts.
我会尽我所能跟议会进行协调的
I will do everything I can in the senate.
- 失陪一下 - 好的
- Excuse me. - Certainly.
阿纳金！
Anakin!
帕德梅  我想你
I've missed you, Padme.
外面有谣言说你死了
There were whispers that you'd been killed.
我不是好好的么
I'm all right.
我觉得我们好象分开了好久好久
It feels like we've been apart for a lifetime.
要不是议长被绑架  可能还回不来呢
And it might have been, if the chancellor hadn't been kidnapped.
在外围星系打仗的话根本回不来
I don't think they would have ever brought us back from the outer rim sieges.
- 等等  别在这里 - 就在这里
- Wait. Not here. - Yes, here.
对这些伪装我厌倦了
I'm tired of all this deception.
我不管他们知不知道我们已经结婚了
I don't care if they know we're married.
阿纳金  别说这种话
Anakin, don't say things like that.
你还好吗?你在发抖
Are you all right? You're trembling.
怎么了?
What's going on?
有一个好消息要告诉你
Something wonderful has happened.
亲爱的  我怀孕了
Ani, I'm pregnant.
那真是太好了
That's wonderful.
那我们该怎么办?
What are we gonna do?
我们现在什么都别担心  好吗?
We're not gonna worry about anything right now. All right?
现在应该是最快乐的
This is a happy moment.
我人生中最快乐的时刻
The happiest moment of my life.
尊贵的西迪厄斯主人
Yes, Lord Sidious?
格里弗斯将军
General Grievous...
你先把分裂分子们带到木法星
I suggest you move the separatist leaders to Mustafar.
好的  陛下
It will be done, my lord.
将军  战争很快就要结束了
The end of the war is near, General.
但是杜库伯爵的不幸...
But the loss of Count Dooku...
他的死是必要的损失
His death was a necessary loss.
很快我就会有一个新的徒弟...
Soon I will have a new apprentice...
他将会更年轻  更强大
one far younger and more powerful.
亲爱的  我想把我们的孩子带回纳布星去
Ani, I want to have our baby back home on Naboo.
我们可以到湖边隐居
We can go to the lake country where no one will know...
那里很安全的
where we can be safe.
我可以先过去  布置好婴儿房
I can go early and fix up the baby's room.
我知道在哪里建最好  就在花园旁边
I know the perfect spot. Right by the gardens.
你真的... 很美
You are so... beautiful.
那是因为我很爱你
It's only because I'm so in love.
不
No.
不  是因为我很爱你
No, it's because I'm so in love with you.
你的意思是情人眼里出西施?
So love has blinded you?
不  我不是这个意思
That's not exactly what I meant.
但也许是这样的
But it's probably true.
阿纳金  救我！
Anakin, help me!
你怎么了?
What's bothering you?
没事
Nothing.
我还记得我是什么时候送这个给你的
I remember when I gave this to you.
要多久我们才可以真正坦诚相对?
How long is it gonna take for us to be honest with each other?
- 我做了个梦 - 恶梦?
- It was a dream. - Bad?
就像那些我母亲死前我做过的梦一样
Like the ones I used to have about my mother, just before she died.
这次呢?
And?
这次换成了你
And it was about you.
告诉我
Tell me.
只是个梦而已
It was only a dream.
你因为难产而死
You die in childbirth.
孩子呢?
And the baby?
我不知道
I don't know.
- 只是个梦而已    - 我不会让这一切成真的
- It was only a dream. - I won't let this one become real.
孩子会改变我们的一生
This baby will change our lives.
女王大概不会允许我呆在议会里了
I doubt the queen will continue to allow me to serve in the senate.
而委员会如果发现你做了父亲的话  你就会被开除的...
If the council discovers you're the father, you'll be expelled...
我知道 我知道
I know. I know.
你说欧比旺可以帮我们吗?
Do you think Obi-Wan might be able to help us?
我们不需要他的帮助
We don't need his help.
孩子是对我们的恩赐
Our baby is a blessing.
前兆?
Premonitions?
前兆
Premonitions.
你见到的这些
These visions you have...
是痛苦的  苦难
They're of pain, suffering.
死亡
Death.
是你自己  还是别人?
Yourself you speak of, or someone you know?
别人
Someone.
亲密的人?
Close to you?
是的
Yes.
当你感知未来的时候  要小心  阿纳金
Careful you must be when sensing the future, Anakin.
对失去的恐惧将带你走进黑暗
The fear of loss is a path to the dark side.
我不可以让这些发生的  尤达大师
I won't let these visions come true, Master Yoda.
死亡是生命中自然的一部分
Death is a natural part of life.
当你身边的人转化为原力时  你应该感到欣喜
Rejoice for those around you who transform into the Force.
不要忧伤  不要想念
Mourn them, do not. Miss them, do not.
依恋将导致嫉妒
Attachment leads to jealousy.
那就是贪婪的影子
The shadow of greed that is.
尤达大师  我该怎么做?
What must I do, Master Yoda?
训练你自己去放开
Train yourself to let go...
那些你害怕失去的东西
of everything you fear to lose.
你没听到外环战况的报告
You've missed the report on the outer rim sieges.
不好意思  我有点事耽搁了
I'm sorry. I was held up.
- 是我的错 - 总言而之  战事非常顺利
- I have no excuse. - In short, they are going very well.
贸易联盟的势力大不如前  沃斯大师把他的军队移到了博兹佩提
Saleucami has fallen, and Master Vos has moved his troops to Boz Pity.
有什么问题?
What's wrong, then?
今天议会要进行投票以决定是否给议长更多的权力
The senate is expected to vote more executive powers to the chancellor today.
哦  那就说明以后要少说话  多做事了  不好吗?
That can only mean less deliberating and more action. Is that bad?
那样我们结束战争就更容易了
It'll make it easier for us to end this war.
提防你的朋友帕尔帕廷议长
Be careful of your friend Palpatine.
提防他什么?
Be careful of what?
- 他指明要你出席 - 为什么?
- He has requested your presence. - What for?
他没说
He would not say.
他没有先通知委员会?很不寻常  是不是?
He didn't inform the council? That's unusual, isn't it?
这一切都很不寻常
All of this is unusual.
所以才让我感到不安
And it's making me feel uneasy.
我希望你相信我  阿纳金
I hope you trust me, Anakin.
当然
Of course.
孩子  我需要你的帮助
I need your help, son.
什么意思?
What do you mean?
我全靠你了
I'm depending on you.
为什么?我不明白
For what? I don't understand.
去做共和国的眼睛、耳朵和声音吧...
To be the eyes, ears and voice of the Republic.
阿纳金...
Anakin...
我将指定你做我在委员会上的私人代表
I'm appointing you to be my personal representative on the Jedi Council.
我?
Me?
当大师?
A master?
我担当不起
I'm overwhelmed, sir.
委员会是自行选择成员的  他们不会接受的
But the council elects its own members. They'll never accept this.
我想他们会的 他们需要你
I think they will. They need you.
比你所想象的更需要
More than you know.
委员会是不会轻易承认这种指派的
Allow this appointment lightly the council does not.
令人不解的是  提出这种要求的是帕尔帕廷议长
Disturbing is this move by Chancellor Palpatine.
我明白
I understand.
你是委员会的成员...
You are on this council...
但是我们不会给你大师头衔
but we do not grant you the rank of master.
什么?
What?
你们怎么可以这样?我无法忍受
How can you do this? This is outrageous.
这不公平
It's unfair.
既是成员  怎么可以没有头衔呢?
How can you be on the council and not be a master?
坐下说  年轻的天行者
Take a seat, young Skywalker.
原谅我  大师
Forgive me, Master.
我们已经检查过共和国内的所有星系
We have surveyed all systems in the Republic...
但是找不到格里弗斯的踪影
but have found no sign of General Grievous.
他一定躲在外围星系里了
Hiding in the outer rim Grievous is.
你们也要检查一下边远的星系
The outlying systems you must sweep.
我们的船不够
We do not have many ships to spare.
另外帝国军攻打伍基人的事情怎么办?
What about the droid attack on the Wookiees?
我们必须马上派出援军
It is critical we send an attack group there immediately.
对  我们不能再失去一个星系了
He's right. It's a system we cannot afford to lose.
我会去的
Go I will.
我跟伍基人的关系很好
Good relations with the Wookiees I have.
那就这么办
It's settled then.
尤达将带一队克隆兵
Yoda will take a battalion of clones
到卡希克支援伍基人
to reinforce the Wookiees on Kashyyyk.
愿原力与我们同在
May the Force be with us all.
这算什么?
What kind of nonsense is this?
让我加入委员会  却不给我大师头衔?
Put me on the council and not make me a master?
绝地武士的历史上从来没有过  这是一种羞辱
It's never been done in the history of the Jedi. It's insulting.
冷静点  阿纳金  你已经很受重用了
Calm down, Anakin. You have been given a great honour.
在你这个年龄就得以加入委员会  这从来都没有过的
To be on the council at your age... it's never happened before.
事实是你跟议长关系太密切了
The fact of the matter is you are too close to the chancellor.
委员会并不喜欢他过多的干涉绝地武士的事务
The council doesn't like it when he interferes in Jedi affairs.
我对你发誓  我没有要求过进入委员会
I swear to you, I didn't ask to be put on the council.
但你心里是这么想的
But it's what you wanted.
你跟议长的交情看来有回报了
Your friendship with Chancellor Palpatine seems to have paid off.
那跟这没有关系
That has nothing to do with this.
委员会批准任命你的唯一理由
The only reason the council has approved your appointment...
就是议长对你的信任
is because the chancellor trusts you.
还有呢?
And?
阿纳金  我是站在你这边的
Anakin, I am on your side.
我不想你陷入这样的状况
I didn't want to put you in this situation.
什么状况?
What situation?
委员会希望你可以报告议长的一举一动
The council wants you to report on all the chancellor's dealings.
他们想知道他到底想做什么
They want to know what he's up to.
他们想让我去监视议长?
They want me to spy on the chancellor?
- 那是叛国   - 我们在战争中  阿纳金
- But that's treason. - We are at war, Anakin.
为什么会议上委员会不直接指派我这项任务?
Why didn't the council give me this assignment when we were in session?
这项任务是不作记录的
This assignment is not to be on record.
议长并没有那么坏  欧比王
The chancellor is not a bad man, Obi-Wan.
他对我很好  从我第一次来就很关照我
He befriended me. He's watched out for me ever since I arrived here.
所以你必须帮助我们
That is why you must help us.
阿纳金  我们效忠的是议会
Anakin, our allegiance is to the senate, not to its leader...
而不是一个任期已满却不肯下台的领导者
who has managed to stay in office long after his term has expired.
是议会让他连任的
The senate demanded that he stay longer.
是的  但是你仔细想想  阿纳金  这样是不是不太合适
Yes, but use your feelings, Anakin. Something is out of place.
你叫我做的事情违背了绝地武士的原则
You're asking me to do something against the Jedi code.
违背了共和国  违背了一位良师和知己
Against the Republic. Against a mentor and a friend.
这些才是不合适的  为什么叫我做这件事?
That's what's out of place here. Why are you asking this of me?
是委员会要你做的
The council is asking you.
阿纳金似乎对他的新任务不太热衷
Anakin did not take to his new assignment with much enthusiasm.
他们两个在一起实在太危险了
It's very dangerous, putting them together.
我觉得这孩子肯定处理不好
I don't think the boy can handle it.
我信不过他
I don't trust him.
大师  冒昧地问一下  难道他不是预言中的那个人吗?
With all due respect, Master, is he not the chosen one?
难道不该是他来毁灭西斯  恢复原力的平衡吗?
Is he not to destroy the Sith and bring balance to the Force?
预言是这么说的
So the prophecy says.
预言也可能误导了我们
A prophecy that misread could have been.
他不会让我失望的
He will not let me down.
从来都没有
He never has.
希望你是对的
I hope right you are.
有时我在想  绝地武士的原则到底怎么了
Sometimes I wonder what's happening to the Jedi order.
我认为战争正在破坏着共和国的法则
I think this war is destroying the principles of the Republic.
你有没有想过也许我们都站错边了?
Have you ever considered that we may be on the wrong side?
什么意思?
What do you mean?
会不会我们一直信奉着的民主政治已经不复存在?
What if the democracy we thought we were serving no longer exists...
共和国是不是已经沦为了我们致力消灭的邪恶组织?
and the Republic has become the very evil we've been fighting to destroy?
我不相信 你怎么听起来像分裂分子
I don't believe that. And you're sounding like a separatist.
这场战争代表了开明政治的失败
This war represents a failure to listen.
现在  你是议长最亲近的人
Now you're closer to the chancellor than anyone.
求你叫他停止战争  恢复民主吧
Please, ask him to stop the fighting and let diplomacy resume.
别跟我说这些
Don't ask me to do that.
这种事情要去跟议会说  我可管不了
Make a motion in the senate, where that kind of a request belongs.
- 怎么了? - 没什么
- What is it? - Nothing.
别这样  别把我也关在心门之外  让我帮助你好吗
Don't do this. Don't shut me out. Let me help you.
抱着我
Hold me.
就像在纳布的湖边
Like you did by the lake on Naboo.
就像以前  我们之间只有爱情
So long ago, when there was nothing but our love.
没有政治  没有算计  没有战争
No politics, no plotting, no war.
- 你有事找我  议长? - 对  阿纳金
- You wanted to see me, Chancellor. - Yes, Anakin.
过来 我有好消息
Come closer. I have good news.
我们的克隆人情报机关...
Our clone intelligence units...
已经找到格里弗斯将军的行踪了
have discovered the location of General Grievous.
他躲在尤塔帕星系
He's hiding in the Utapau system.
可找到他了
At last.
终于可以抓到这个大魔头结束战争了
We'll be able to capture that monster and end this war.
如果委员会不派你参与此项任务的话
I would worry about the collective wisdom of the council...
我将对他们的集体智慧产生怀疑
if it didn't select you for this assignment.
目前为止  你是最佳的选择
You're the best choice, by far.
坐下
Sit down.
你们退下
Leave us.
阿纳金
Anakin.
你知道我不能依赖于绝地委员会
You know I'm not able to rely on the Jedi Council.
如果他们还没把你纳入计划  他们很快也会和你说的
If they haven't included you in their plot, they soon will.
我不太明白您的意思
I'm not sure I understand.
你应该感觉得到我的疑虑
You must sense what I have come to suspect.
绝地委员会想完全控制共和国
The Jedi Council want control of the Republic.
他们计划背叛我
They're planning to betray me.
- 我想不是吧... - 阿纳金
- I don't think that... - Anakin.
你好好感觉一下
Search your feelings.
你知道的  不是吗?
You know, don't you?
我知道他们不信任你
I know they don't trust you.
或者是议会 或是共和国
Or the senate. Or the Republic.
或是民主  就此而言
Or democracy, for that matter.
我必须承认  我对他们的信任已经动摇了
I have to admit, my trust in them has been shaken.
为什么?
Why?
是不是他们让你做一些
They asked you to do something that
有悖你良心的事情?
made you feel dishonest, didn't they?
他们让你监视我  是不是?
They asked you to spy on me, didn't they?
我不知道...
I don't...
我不知道该说些什么
I don't know what to say.
还记得以前的教诲吧
Remember back to your early teachings.
“所有获得权力的人都会害怕失去权力”
All who gain power are afraid to lose it.
- 绝地武士也是如此 - 绝地武士是用他们的力量行善
- Even the Jedi. - The Jedi use their power for good.
所谓的“善”不过是相对而言  阿纳金
Good is a point of view, Anakin.
西斯和绝地武士在几乎所有方面都相似
The Sith and the Jedi are similar in almost every way...
包括对更强力量的追求
including their quest for greater power.
西斯依赖内心的激情去获取力量
The Sith rely on their passion for their strength.
他们只在乎自身
They think inwards... only about themselves.
难道绝地武士不是这样?
And the Jedi don't?
绝地武士很无私  他们只关心他人
The Jedi are selfless. They only care about others.
你听说过西斯黑暗君主  达斯.普雷厄斯的悲剧吗?
Did you ever hear the tragedy of Darth Plagueis the Wise?
没有
No.
我想也是 绝地武士是不会把这故事告诉你的
I thought not. It's not a story the Jedi would tell you.
这是一个西斯的传说
It's a Sith legend.
达斯.普雷厄斯曾是西斯的一位黑暗君主...
Darth Plagueis was a dark lord of the Sith...
非常强大而且充满智慧...
so powerful and so wise...
他甚至可以使用原力影响迷地原虫
he could use the Force to influence the midi-chlorians...
来创造生命
to create... life.
他对黑暗原力如此的了解
He had such a knowledge of the dark side...
使他可以让自己关心的人
he could even keep the ones he cared about...
起死回生
from dying.
他真的可以...让人起死回生?
He could actually... save people from death?
原力黑暗的一面可以通往许多奇异能力
The dark side of the Force is a pathway to many abilities...
有些被认为是非自然的
some consider to be unnatural.
他后来怎么样?
What happened to him?
他变得非常强大
He became so powerful...
他在这世上只害怕一件事
the only thing he was afraid of was...
就是失去他的力量
losing his power.
但最终他还是失去了力量
Which eventually, of course, he did.
他把所有的知识传授给了他的徒弟
Unfortunately, he taught his apprentice everything he knew.
因此他徒弟就趁他睡觉时将他杀了
Then his apprentice killed him in his sleep.
真是讽刺
It's ironic.
他可以让别人起死回生
He could save others from death...
但却无法救他自己
but not himself.
有可能学到这种力量吗?
Is it possible to learn this power?
从绝地武士那里可学不到
Not from a Jedi.
所有红色单位   到这边集合！
All Red units, over here!
帕尔帕廷认为格里弗斯将军在尤塔帕星球?
Palpatine thinks General Grievous is on Utapau?
截获了只言片语...
A partial message was intercepted...
从尤塔帕星首领发出的一份外交信息中
in a diplomatic packet from the chairman of Utapau.
我们必须行动起来
Act on this we must.
抓住格里弗斯将军就可以结束这场战争
The capture of General Grievous will end this war.
我们必须速战速决
Quickly and decisively we should proceed.
议长要求由我来领导这次战役
The chancellor has requested... that I lead the campaign.
这事由绝地委员会决定
The council will make up its own mind who is to go...
议长无权干涉
not the chancellor.
我们需要一位经验丰富的大师
A master is needed, with more experience.
我推举  由克诺比大师领衔
I concur. Master Kenobi should go.
我同意
I agree.
同意
Aye.
很好  会议结束
Very well. Council adjourned.
机器人部队已经启动了主发电机
The droids have started up their main power generators.
- 是时候开战了  指挥官 - 是的  长官
- Then now the time is, Commander. - Yes, sir.
冲啊！
Charge!
注意掩护！
Head for cover!
- 这次你需要我的帮助   - 我同意
- You're gonna need me on this one. - I agree.
不过  搞不好这次会变成一场班沙星的追逐
However, it may turn out just to be a wild bantha chase.
师父
Master.
我让你失望了
I've disappointed you.
我并不是很感激你对我的栽培之恩
I haven't been very appreciative of your training.
我一直都自以为是  我很抱歉
I've been arrogant, and I apologize.
我对绝地委员会感到非常失望
I've just been so frustrated with the council.
你既强大又聪明  阿纳金  我以你为荣
You are strong and wise, Anakin, and I am very proud of you.
我从小就开始训练你
I have trained you since you were a small boy.
我所知道的一切都已经教给你了
I have taught you everything I know.
你已经成为一名真正的绝地武士  甚至超出了我的期望
And you have become a far greater Jedi than I could ever hope to be.
但是耐心点  阿纳金
But be patient, Anakin.
绝地委员会很快就会让你成为大师的
It will not be long before the council makes you a Jedi master.
欧比旺  愿原力与你同在
Obi-Wan. May the Force be with you.
再见  老朋友  愿原力与你同在
Goodbye, old friend. May the Force be with you.
幸运的是  大部分城市
Fortunately, most of the cities are
都集中在这一小块大陆
concentrated on this small continent here.
在远端
On the far side.
我会吸引他们的注意力  直到你们到达
I'll keep them distracted until you get there.
只要别太久就行
Just don't take too long.
得了  我何时让你失望过?
Come on. When have I ever let you down?
非常好  我身上的累赘就是
Very well. The burden is on me
在你们到来之前不会干掉所有的机器人士兵
not to destroy all the droids until you arrive.
节省点力气
Save your energy.
我做不到
I can't.
不要放弃  帕德梅
Don't give up, Padm?
欧比旺来过  对吧?
Obi-Wan's been here, hasn't he?
他今早来过
He came by this morning.
他想要干嘛?
What did he want?
他很担心你
He's worried about you.
他说你最近承受着很大的压力
He says you've been under a lot of stress.
我感觉自己迷失了
I feel lost.
迷失了?什么意思?
Lost? What do you mean?
欧比旺和绝地委员会不信任我
Obi-Wan and the council don't trust me.
他们用自己的生命来信任你
They trust you with their lives.
发生了一些事情
Something's happening.
我并不是一个称职的绝地武士
I'm not the Jedi I should be.
我想要更多
I want more.
但我知道自己不应该
And I know I shouldn't.
你对自己期望过多了
You expect too much of yourself.
- 我找到了救你的方法 - 救我?
- I found a way to save you. - Save me?
从我的梦魇中
From my nightmares.
是这事一直困扰着你吗?
Is that what's bothering you?
我不会失去你的  帕德梅
I won't lose you, Padm?
我不会难产而死的  亲爱的
I'm not gonna die in childbirth, Ani.
- 我向你保证 - 不  我向你保证
- I promise you. - No, I promise you.
你好  年轻的绝地武士
Greetings, young Jedi.
你为什么来到我们这颗遥远的避难行星?
What brings you to our remote sanctuary?
很不幸  是因为战争
Unfortunately, the war.
这里没有战争  除非你带来了战争
There's no war here... unless you brought it with you.
如果你允许的话  我想补充点燃料
With your kind permission, I should like some fuel...
同时借用你的城市作为基地
and to use your city as a base
在附近行星搜寻格里弗斯将军
as I search nearby systems for General Grievous.
他就在这里  我们全是人质
He is here. We are being held hostage.
- 他们正在监视着我们 - 我明白了
- They are watching us. - I understand.
他们在第十层  有成千上万的战斗机器人
Tenth level, thousands of battle droids.
让你的人民做好避难准备
Tell your people to take shelter.
如果你有士兵  现在是派上用场的时候了
If you have warriors, now is the time.
把战斗机开回母舰去  告诉科迪  我已经联系好了
Take the fighter back to the ship. Tell Cody I've made contact.
- 他会带更多的士兵来吗? - 他没说
- Is he bringing additional warriors? - He didn't say.
共和国的军队很快就会追踪到这里
It won't be long before the armies of the Republic track us here.
我要你们到外围星系的穆斯塔法去
I am sending you to the Mustafar system in the outer rim.
那是一个多火山的星球
It is a volcanic planet.
- 在那里你会安全的 - 安全?
- You will be safe there. - Safe?
将军  你让帕尔帕廷议长从你手上溜掉
Chancellor Palpatine managed to escape your grip, General.
没有了杜库伯爵  我怀疑你是否还有能力保障我们的安全
Without Count Dooku, I have doubts about your ability to keep us safe.
说谢谢吧  总督  你得庆幸没有落到我的手上
Be thankful, Viceroy, you have not found yourself in my grip.
你们的飞船准备好了
Your ship is waiting.
大家好
Hello there.
克诺比将军
General Kenobi.
你真是有勇无谋
You are a bold one.
干掉他
Kill him.
后退
Back away.
我亲自来对付这个绝地废物
I will deal with this Jedi slime myself.
你出招吧
Your move.
你这傻瓜
You fool.
杜库伯爵曾教过我你们绝地武士的剑术
I've been trained in your Jedi arts by Count Dooku.
出招吧  克诺比
Attack, Kenobi.
不管你有没有军队
Army or not...
你得知道自己已经大难临头了
you must realize you are doomed.
我可不这样想
I don't think so.
掩护那边
Cover that corner.
温杜大师  我可以打断一下吗?
Master Windu, may I interrupt?
克诺比将军已和格里弗斯将军交上手
General Kenobi has made contact with General Grievous...
我们已经开始进攻了
and we have begun our attack.
谢谢你  指挥官
Thank you, Commander.
阿纳金  把这报告转呈议长
Anakin, deliver this report to the chancellor.
他的反应会暴露他的意图
His reaction will give us a clue to his intentions.
是的  大师
Yes, Master.
我感觉有人在密谋毁灭绝地武士
I sense a plot to destroy the Jedi.
黑暗原力笼罩着议长
The dark side of the Force surrounds the chancellor.
如果他不愿放弃他的紧急权力...
If he does not give up his emergency powers...
在格里弗斯被歼灭后...
after the destruction of Grievous...
那他应该被逐出政府
then he should be removed from office.
绝地委员会应该接管议会
The Jedi Council would have to take control of the senate...
以便权力能安全和平地移交
in order to secure a peaceful transition.
也许这想法会将我们带入绝境
To a dark place this line of thought will carry us.
我们必须得小心行事
Great care we must take.
议长
Chancellor.
我们刚收到克诺比大师发来的报告
We've just received a report from Master Kenobi.
他已和格里弗斯将军交战了
He has engaged General Grievous.
我们只能希望克诺比大师能够应付这次挑战
We can only hope that Master Kenobi is up to the challenge.
我应该到那里和他并肩战斗
I should be there with him.
看起来绝地委员会并不完全认同你的才能
It's upsetting to me to see that the council...
这让我很难过
doesn't seem to fully appreciate your talents.
你难道不想知道他们为何不让你成为绝地大师吗?
Don't you wonder why they won't make you a Jedi master?
我希望自己知道原因
I wish I knew.
我越来越觉得自己
More and more I get the feeling that...
被排斥在绝地委员会之外
I'm being excluded from the council.
我知道他们没有把有些关于原力的知识告诉我
I know there are things about the Force that they're not telling me.
他们不信任你  阿纳金
They don't trust you, Anakin.
他们看到了你的未来
They see your future.
他们知道你的力量会超越他们的控制
They know your power will be too strong to control.
你必须看穿这些谎言迷雾
You must break through the fog of lies
绝地武士散布在你周围的的谎言
the Jedi have created around you.
让我帮助你了解原力的奥妙
Let me help you to know the subtleties of the Force.
你怎么会知道使用原力的方法?
How do you know the ways of the Force?
我师父教会了我所有关于原力的知识
My mentor taught me everything about the Force.
甚至包括黑暗原力的本质
Even the nature of the dark side.
你了解黑暗原力?
You know the dark side?
阿纳金
Anakin.
如果一个人想要通晓原力的奥妙
If one is to understand the great mystery...
就必须研究其方方面面
one must study all its aspects...
而不仅仅是绝地武士那些狭隘的教条
not just the dogmatic narrow view of the Jedi.
如果你想成为一位睿智、十足的领袖人物
If you wish to become a complete and wise leader...
你必须更多的去了解原力
you must embrace a larger view of the Force.
小心那些绝地武士  阿纳金
Be careful of the Jedi, Anakin.
只有通过我你才能获得比绝地武士更强大的力量
Only through me can you achieve a power greater than any Jedi.
学会了使用黑暗原力
Learn to know the dark side of the Force...
你就可以把你的妻子
and you will be able to save your wife...
从死亡的命运中解救出来
from certain death.
你说什么?
What did you say?
希望你能运用我的知识
Use my knowledge. I beg you.
你是西斯君主
You're the Sith lord.
我知道是什么困扰着你  听我说
I know what's been troubling you. Listen to me.
别再继续当绝地委员会手中的小卒子
Don't continue to be a pawn of the Jedi Council.
从我认识你起  你就在追寻一种
Ever since I've known you, you've been searching for a life...
比寻常绝地武士更为伟大的人生
greater than that of an ordinary Jedi.
一种具有重要意义的人生
A life of significance...
一种道德的人生
of conscience.
- 你想要杀我吗?    - 我当然会这样做
- Are you going to kill me? - I would certainly like to.
我知道你会
I know you would.
我能感受到你的愤怒
I can feel your anger.
它使你全神贯注
It gives you focus...
使你更加强大
makes you stronger.
我要把你交给绝地委员会
I'm going to turn you over to the Jedi Council.
当然你该这么做
Of course. You should.
但是你并不清楚他们的目的  对吧?
But you're not sure of their intentions, are you?
我很快就会发现这一切的真相
I will quickly discover the truth of all this.
你很聪明  阿纳金
You have great wisdom, Anakin.
来了解黑暗原力吧
Know the power of the dark side.
这是一种可以拯救帕德梅的力量
Power to save Padm?
真原始
So uncivilized.
温杜大师  我得和你谈谈
Master Windu, I must talk to you.
天行者  我们刚得知
Skywalker, we just received word that
欧比旺消灭了格里弗斯将军
Obi-Wan has destroyed General Grievous.
现在我们去确保...
We're on our way to make sure...
议长将紧急特权交还议会
the chancellor returns emergency power back to the senate.
他不会放弃他的权力  我刚得知一个可怕的事实
He won't give up his power. I've just learned a terrible truth.
我想帕尔帕廷议长就是西斯君主
I think Chancellor Palpatine is a Sith lord.
西斯君主?
A Sith lord?
是的  就是我们一直在寻找的家伙
Yes. The one we've been looking for.
- 你怎么会知道这事? - 他懂得原力
- How do you know this? - He knows the ways of the Force.
他受过使用黑暗原力的训练
He's been trained to use the dark side.
- 你确信? - 完全确信
- Are you sure? - Absolutely.
那我们最害怕的事就成真了
Then our worst fears have been realized.
为了绝地武士团的生死存亡  我们得赶快行动
We must move quickly if the Jedi order is to survive.
大师  议长非常强大
Master, the chancellor is very powerful.
如果你要去逮捕他  你需要我的帮助
You'll need my help if you're going to arrest him.
你还是不要插手此事为好
For you own good, stay out of this affair.
我能感觉到你内心的迷惑  年轻的天行者
I sense a great deal of confusion in you, young Skywalker.
恐惧蒙蔽了你的判断力
There is much fear that clouds your judgement.
- 大师  我必须去 - 不行
- I must go, Master. - No.
如果你所言属实  你就会得到我的信任
If what you've told me is true, you will have gained my trust.
但现在  留在这里
But for now, remain here.
在绝地委员会议事厅等我们回来
Wait in the council chambers until we return.
是的  大师
Yes, Master.
你知道的  对吧?
You do know, don't you...
如果绝地武士杀掉了我
if theJedi destroy me...
你就无望拯救她的生命了
any chance of saving her will be lost.
温杜大师  我猜格里弗斯将军已被歼灭
Master Windu. I take it General Grievous has been destroyed then.
你们比我想的干得还要快
I must say you're here sooner than expected.
以银河共和国议会的名义
In the name of the Galactic Senate of the Republic...
你被逮了  议长
you're under arrest, Chancellor.
你在威胁我吗  大师?
Are you threatening me, Master Jedi?
议会将决定你的命运
The senate will decide your fate.
- 我就是议会  - 还不是
- I am the senate. - Not yet.
那这就是叛变行为
It's treason then.
你被捕了  君主殿下
You are under arrest, my lord.
阿纳金  我告诉过你他们会这样做 我说对了
Anakin, I told you it would come to this. I was right.
绝地武士想要篡权
The Jedi are taking over.
西斯横行的时代过去了
The oppression of the Sith will never return.
你已经输了
You have lost.
不
No.
不！  才不！
No! No!
要死的是你！
You will die!
他是个叛徒！
He's a traitor!
他才是叛徒！
He is the traitor!
我有能力拯救你爱的人
I have the power to save the one you love.
你必须作出选择
You must choose.
别听他的  阿纳金！
Don't listen to him, Anakin!
别让他杀我
Don't let him kill me.
我坚持不住了...
I can't hold it any longer.
我不行了 我很虚弱
I can't. I'm weak.
太虚弱了
I'm too weak.
阿纳金
Anakin.
救救我！
Help me. Help me!
我坚持不下去了
I can't hold on any longer.
我现在就能解决你  一劳永逸
I am going to end this once and for all.
你不能...
You can't.
他必须接受审判
He must stand trial.
他已经控制了议会和法院
He has control of the senate and the courts.
他太危险了  必须除掉他
He's too dangerous to be left alive.
我太虚弱了
I'm too weak.
- 求你饶我一命 - 这不是绝地武士的处事方式
- Don't kill me. Please. - It's not the Jedi way.
他必须活下去
He must live.
- 请别杀他 - 我需要他
- Please don't. - I need him.
- 别这样！   - 不！
- Please don't! - No!
力量！
Power!
无尽的力量！
Unlimited power!
我干了什么?
What have I done?
你在履践自己的命运  阿纳金
You're fulfilling your destiny, Anakin.
成为我的徒弟
Become my apprentice.
研习黑暗原力
Learn to use the dark side of the Force.
我听从你的吩咐
I will do whatever you ask.
很好
Good.
只要你能助我拯救帕德梅的生命
Just help me save Padm?s life.
没有她我也不能独活
I can't live without her.
古往今来只有一人曾习得起死回生之术...
To cheat death is a power only one has achieved...
但如果我们一起研习...
but if we work together...
我肯定我们能洞悉其奥秘
I know we can discover the secret.
我发誓忠于...
I pledge myself...
您的教诲
to your teachings.
好
Good.
很好
你的原力很强
The Force is strong with you.
你将会成一个无比强大的西斯
A powerful Sith you will become.
从今以后  你将被认为是...
Henceforth you shall be known as...
达斯... 维德
Darth... Vader.
感谢您  我的恩师
Thank you, my master.
免礼
Rise.
我年轻的徒弟  因为绝地委员会不信任你
Because the council did not trust you, my young apprentice...
所以我相信你是唯一对他们的阴谋毫不知情的绝地武士
I believe you are the only Jedi with no knowledge of this plot.
如果那些绝地武士知道了他们的阴谋已经败露
When the Jedi learn what has transpired here...
他们会杀掉我们  连同所有的参议员一起
they will kill us, along with all the senators.
我同意
I agree.
绝地委员会下一步就会推翻议会
The council's next move will be against the senate.
每一名绝地武士
Every single Jedi...
包括你的好友欧比旺.克诺比...
including your friend Obi-Wan Kenobi...
现在都是共和国的敌人
is now an enemy of the Republic.
我明白  师父
I understand, Master.
我们得赶快行动
We must move quickly.
这些绝地武士冷酷无情
The Jedi are relentless.
如果不将他们赶尽杀绝  恐怕这场内战永无止息
If they are not all destroyed, it will be civil war without end.
首先  我要你去绝地圣殿
First I want you to go to the Jedi temple.
我们要攻他们一个措手不及
We will catch them off-balance.
去做该做的事吧  维德勋爵
Do what must be done, Lord Vader.
不要犹豫不决  不要心慈手软
Do not hesitate. Show no mercy.
只有那样你才会有足够强大的黑暗原力
Only then will you be strong enough with the dark side...
以拯救帕德梅
to save Padm?
那其他分散在星系间的绝地武士怎么办?
What about the other Jedi spread across the galaxy?
他们的背叛行为会得到处置
Their betrayal will be dealt with.
在你干掉圣殿里的绝地武士后
After you have killed all the Jedi in the temple...
赶往穆斯塔法
go to the Mustafar system.
杀掉刚雷总督
Wipe out Viceroy Gunray...
和其他分裂分子的首领
and the other separatist leaders.
西斯将再一次一统整个星系！
Once more the Sith will rule the galaxy!
同时
And...
我们将会得到和平
we shall have... peace.
中士  过来！
Sergeant, over here!
所有人快跟上！
Hurry! All of them!
所有红色单位  干掉它！
All Red units, let's move it!
过来  出发！
Come on. Let's go!
指挥官  联系你的部队
Commander, contact your troops.
叫他们去占领高层
Tell them to move to the higher levels.
是的  长官
Very good, sir.
对了  我想您会需要这个
By the way, I think you'll be needing this.
谢谢你  科迪  快行动  我们得尽快赢下这场战斗
Thank you, Cody. Let's get a move on. We've got a battle to win.
遵命
Yes, sir.
科迪指挥官...
Commander Cody...
时机成熟了
the time has come.
执行66号令
Execute order 66.
是的  陛下
Yes, my lord.
轰掉他！
Blast him!
跟我来！
Come on!
执行66号令
Execute order 66.
遵命  陛下
It will be done, my lord.
天行者大师  敌人太多了
Master Skywalker, there are too many of them.
我们该怎么办?
What are we going to do?
从议长办公室传来的消息
The chancellor's office indicated
说阿纳金主人回绝地圣殿了
Master Anakin returned to the Jedi temple.
别太担心  夫人  我肯定他不会有事的
Don't worry. I'm sure he'll be all right.
- 这是怎么了? - 发生了叛乱  阁下
- What's going on here? - There's been a rebellion, sir.
别担心  局势已在我们的控制之下
Don't worry. The situation is under control.
对不起  阁下  您该走了
I'm sorry, sir. It's time for you to leave.
的确如此
And so it is.
干掉他！
Get him!
不！
No!
不用管他  让他去吧
Don't worry about him. Let him go.
所有的胡基人全死了  赶去东线
All these Wookiees are dead. Move to the east.
是的  长官
Yes, sir.
再见  塔弗尔
Goodbye, Tarfful.
再见  丘巴卡
Goodbye, Chewbacca.
我会想你们的
Miss you I will.
希望我能及时拯救一部分绝地武士...
Hopefully we'll be able to intercept a few Jedi...
在他们卷入这场灾难之前
before they walk into this catastrophe.
你找到克诺比了吗?
Did you find Kenobi?
长官  这么高掉下去无人能存活
Sir, no one could have survived that fall.
让你的人上飞船
Start loading your men on the ships.
赶快
Move it.
九一三号紧急代码
Emergency code 913.
我在所有频段都联系不上
I have no contact on any frequency.
克诺比大师
Master Kenobi.
- 重复 - 克诺比大师
- Repeat. - Master Kenobi.
奥加纳参议员  我的克隆人部队伏击我  我需要帮助
Senator Organa. My clone troops turned on me. I need help.
我们刚刚救出了尤达大师
We havejust rescued Master Yoda.
这种都有人遭到暗算
It appears this ambush has happened everywhere.
我们把坐标传给你
We're sending you our coordinates.
嘘！  轻一点
Hush! Not so loud.
你没事吧?我听说有人袭击了绝地圣殿
Are you all right? I heard there was an attack on the Jedi temple.
- 从这里都能看见冒出来的烟 - 我没事
- You could see the smoke from here. - I'm fine.
我来看看你和孩子是否安全
I came to see if you and the baby are safe.
发生什么事了?
What's happening?
绝地武士想颠覆共和国
The Jedi have tried to overthrow the Republic.
难以置信
I can't believe that.
我亲眼看到温杜大师试图刺杀议长
I saw Master Windu attempt to assassinate the chancellor myself.
阿纳金  你打算怎么办?
Oh, Anakin. What are you gonna do?
我不会背叛共和国...
I will not betray the Republic.
我效忠于议长...
My loyalties lie with the chancellor...
议会... 和你
and with the senate and with you.
- 那欧比旺呢? - 我不知道
- What about Obi-Wan? - I don't know.
许多绝地武士已被处决
Many Jedi have been killed.
我们只能希望他仍忠于议长
We can only hope that he's remained loyal to the chancellor.
阿纳金  我害怕
Anakin, I'm afraid.
相信我  我的爱人
Have faith, my love.
这一切很快就会变好的
Everything will soon be set right.
议长交给我一件非常重要的任务
The chancellor has given me a very important mission.
分裂主义分子现在聚集在穆斯塔法系
The separatists have gathered on the Mustafar system.
我要去那里结束这场战争 等我回来
I'm going there to end this war. Wait for me until I return.
我保证  一切都会不同的
Things will be different. I promise.
请等我回来
Please, wait for me.
他承受着很大的压力  R2
Well, he is under a lot of stress, R2.
保重  我的小朋友
Take care, my little friend.
夫人  有什么我能效劳的吗?
Oh, my lady, is there anything I might do?
不用  谢谢你  3PO
No, thank you, 3PO.
我感到很无助
I feel so helpless.
还有多少绝地武士生还?
How many other Jedi have managed to survive?
我们还没有消息
Heard from no one have we.
我看见成千上万的军队攻击绝地圣殿
I saw thousands of troops attack the Jedi temple.
所以我才来找尤达
That's why I went looking for Yoda.
圣殿里的人有消息么?
Have we had any contact from the temple?
我们收到了一条加密的撤退讯息
Received a coded retreat message we have.
要求所有的绝地武士回到圣殿里去
It requests all Jedi to return to the temple.
- 讯息说战争结束了 - 那么我们必须得回去
- It says the war is over. - Then we must go back.
如果有任何士兵掉队了
If there are any stragglers,
他们会落进陷阱而被杀的
they will fall into the trap and be killed.
你是想去撤销那个加密信号?
Suggest dismantling the coded signal, do you?
是的  大师  我们冒不起这个险
Yes, Master. There is too much at stake.
我同意
I agree.
多知道一些事会让我们的前途更光明
And a little more knowledge might light our way.
计划如你所预料的正在顺利进行  我的主人
The plan has gone as you had promised, my lord.
干的不错  总督
You have done well, Viceroy.
我的新徒弟  达斯.维德到了以后
When my new apprentice Darth Vader arrives...
他会关照你们的
he will take care of you.
我们从议长办公室收到一条讯息  长官
We're receiving a message from the chancellor's office, sir.
- 接过来 - 好的  长官
- Send it through. - Yes, sir.
奥加纳参议员  共和国最高议长要求你出席
Senator Organa, the supreme chancellor requests your presence...
议会的特别会议
at a special session of Congress.
- 我会去的 - 他会恭候您的到来
- I will be there. - He'll be expecting you.
- 这可能是个陷阱 - 我觉得不是
- Could be a trap. - I don't think so.
议长是没有办法
The chancellor will not be able to
控制上千之众的星系的...
control the thousands of star systems...
除非议院保持不变
without keeping the senate intact.
有这个特别会议
If a special session of Congress there is...
更方便我们进入绝地圣殿
easier for us to enter the Jedi temple it will be.
R2...呆在飞船这儿
R2, stay with the ship.
欢迎  维德勋爵  恭候大驾已多时
Welcome, Lord Vader. We've been expecting you.
绝地武士的叛变已经被挫败
And the Jedi rebellion has been foiled.
发生什么事了?
What's happened?
议长正在解释说...
The chancellor's been elaborating on...
绝地武士阴谋推翻议会
a plot by the Jedi to overthrow the senate.
余下的绝地武士会被追剿并打败
The remaining Jedi will be hunted down and defeated.
连幼徒们也没放过
Not even the younglings survived.
这名弟子不是被克隆兵杀死的
Killed not by clones this Padawan.
是激光剑刺死的
By a lightsabre he was.
是谁?
Who?
这是谁干的?
Who could have done this?
针对我的刺杀行动...
The attempt on my life...
让我留下伤痕、容颜尽毁
has left me scarred and deformed.
但我保证
But I assure you.
我的决心从来没有这么坚定过！
My resolve has never been stronger!
住手！
Stop!
为了保证社会的安全和长期稳定...
In order to ensure the security and continuing stability...
共和国将重组
the Republic will be reorganized...
成为第一个银河帝国！
into the first Galactic Empire!
为了一个安全而稳定的社会
For a safe and secure society.
自由就是这样死去的
So this is how liberty dies.
伴随着雷鸣般的掌声...
With thunderous applause.
战争结束了
The war is over.
西迪厄斯大人保证给我们和平的  我们只想要...
Lord Sidious promised us peace. We only want...
我重新调校了信号  警告所有幸存的武士别回来
I have recalibrated the code, warning all surviving Jedi to stay away.
对于克隆兵来说
For the clones...
要发现信号被改过了还要很久
to discover the recalibration a long time it will take.
等等  大师
Wait. Master.
有些事我必须弄明白
There is something I must know.
如果去看保安录像  你发现的只会是痛苦
If into the security recordings you go, only pain will you find.
我必须知道真相  大师
I must know the truth, Master.
不可能...
It can't be.
做得漂亮  我的新徒弟
You have done well, my new apprentice.
现在  维德勋爵
Now, Lord Vader...
去给帝国带来和平吧
go and bring peace to the Empire.
我看不下去了
I can't watch any more.
我们必须消灭西斯
Destroy the Sith we must.
派我去刺杀皇帝吧
Send me to kill the emperor.
对阿纳金我下不了手
I will not kill Anakin.
去杀西迪厄斯  你还不够强
To fight this Lord Sidious, strong enough you are not.
他就像我的兄弟... 我下不了手
He is like my brother. I cannot do it.
年轻的天行者已经被黑暗势力扭曲
Twisted by the dark side young Skywalker has become.
你训导的那个孩子  已经不在了
The boy you trained, gone he is.
取而代之的是达斯.维德
Consumed by Darth Vader.
我不知道西迪厄斯把他派到哪里去了
I do not know where the emperor has sent him.
我不知道到哪去找他
I don't know where to look.
用你的感应  欧比旺  你会找到他的
Use your feelings, Obi-Wan, and find him you will.
你最后一次看到他是什么时候?
When was the last time you saw him?
- 昨天 - 你知道他现在在哪儿么?
- Yesterday. - And do you know where he is now?
不知道
No.
帕德梅  我需要你的帮助
Padme, I need your help.
- 他现在非常危险 - 因为西斯?
- He is in grave danger. - From the Sith?
因为他自己
From himself.
帕德梅...
Padme...
阿纳金已经投向黑暗势力了
Anakin has turned to the dark side.
你弄错了  你怎么能那么说?
You're wrong. How could you even say that?
我看到一段全息安保录象... 记录他...
I have seen a security hologram... of him...
怎样屠杀了幼徒们
killing younglings.
不可能是阿纳金  他不会那么做的
Not Anakin. He couldn't.
他被谎言蒙蔽了  我们都是
He was deceived by a lie. We all were.
这一切都是议长的阴谋
It appears that the chancellor is behind everything,
包括战争在内
including the war.
帕尔帕廷就是我们一直在找的西斯君主
Palpatine is the Sith lord we've been looking for.
在杜库伯爵死后  阿纳金成了他的新徒弟
After the death of Count Dooku, Anakin became his new apprentice.
我不信...
I don't believe you.
我不信
I can't.
帕德梅...
Padme...
我必须找到他
I must find him.
你要去杀死他  是么?
You're going to kill him, aren't you?
他已经成为一个非常大的威胁
He has become a very great threat.
我不能
I can't.
阿纳金是孩子的爸爸  对么?
Anakin is the father, isn't he?
我很难过
I'm so sorry.
- 女士  让我和你一起去  - 没有危险了
- Milady, let me come with you. - There's no danger.
战斗结束了  只是点私事
The fighting's over. And this is personal.
如你所愿  女士  但我强烈反对
As you wish, milady, but I strongly disagree.
我不会有事的  队长  有些事我必须亲自去做
I'll be all right, Captain. This is something I must do myself.
而且3PO会照顾我的
Besides, 3PO will look after me.
哦，老天爷
Oh, dear.
知道吗?我发现自己...
Do you know? I think I'm beginning to...
开始掌握飞行技术了
get the hang of this flying business.
分裂分子已经被我消灭了  师傅
The separatists have been taken care of, my master.
你的任务完成了
It is finished then.
你把和平和正义又带回到了星系
You have restored peace and justice to the galaxy.
向贸易联盟的舰队发条消息
Send a message to the ships of the Trade Federation.
所有机器人军团要立即关闭
All droid units must shut down immediately.
很好  主人
Very good, my lord.
我看到了你的飞船
I saw your ship.
- 你来这干吗? - 我好担心你啊
- What are you doing out here? - I was so worried about you.
欧比旺告诉了我一些可怕的事
Obi-Wan told me terrible things.
什么事?
What things?
他说你投靠了黑暗势力
He said you've turned to the dark side.
并且你...还杀死了幼徒
That you... killed younglings.
欧比旺是想让你对付我
Obi-Wan is trying to turn you against me.
他是关心我们的
He cares about us.
我们?
Us?
他知道了
He knows.
他想帮你
He wants to help you.
阿纳金  我要的只是你的爱
Anakin, all I want is your love.
爱救不了你  帕德梅
Love won't save you, Padm?
- 只有我的新力量能救你 - 那值得么?
- Only my new powers can do that. - At what cost?
你是个好人  别这么做
You're a good person. Don't do this.
我不会像失去我母亲一样失去你的
I won't lose you the way I lost my mother.
我现在比任何绝地武士所梦想过的都要强大
I am becoming more powerful than any Jedi has ever dreamed of.
我这么做是为了你  为了保护你
And I'm doing it for you. To protect you.
和我一起走吧
Come away with me.
和我一起把孩子养大
Help me raise our child.
在事情不可收拾前  离开这一切
Leave everything else behind while we still can.
你没看出来么?我们不需要再逃避了
Don't you see? We don't have to run away any more.
我给共和国带来了和平
I have brought peace to the Republic.
我比议长更有力量
I am more powerful than the chancellor.
我可以推翻他
I can overthrow him.
然后我们就可以一起控制整个星系了
And together, you and I can rule the galaxy...
我们想怎样就怎样
make things the way we want them to be.
我真不敢相信...
I don't believe what I'm hearing.
欧比旺没错  你变了
Obi-Wan was right. You've changed.
我不想再听到欧比旺的事了
I don't want to hear any more about Obi-Wan.
绝地武士背叛了我  你不可以背叛我
The Jedi turned against me. Don't you turn against me.
我不认得你了
I don't know you any more.
阿纳金...
Anakin...
你伤透了我的心
You're breaking my heart.
你走的这条路我跟不上
You're going down a path I can't follow.
是因为欧比旺?
Because of Obi-Wan?
是因为你所做的一切
Because of what you've done.
你的计划
What you plan to do.
现在停手  回头吧
Stop. Stop now. Come back.
- 我爱你  - 骗子！
- I love you. - Liar!
不
No.
你是和他一伙的！  你把他带过来杀我的
You're with him! You brought him here to kill me.
放开她  阿纳金
Let her go, Anakin.
放开她
Let her go.
你唆使她背叛了我！
You turned her against me!
是你自作自受
You have done that yourself.
你不能把她从我身边夺走！
You will not take her from me!
你的愤怒和对权力的渴望已经迫使她离开你了
Your anger and your lust for power have already done that.
你让这黑暗的邪王吞噬你的思想...
You have allowed this dark lord to twist your mind...
直到现在你变成了你曾发誓要消灭的人
until now you have become the very thing you swore to destroy.
别和我讲道理  欧比旺
Don't lecture me, Obi-Wan.
我看透了绝地武士的谎言
I see through the lies of the Jedi.
我不像你那么惧怕黑暗势力
I do not fear the dark side as you do.
我给我的新的帝国带来了...
I have brought peace...
和平 自由  正义和安全
freedom, justice and security to my new empire.
你的新帝国?
Your new empire?
别逼我杀了你
Don't make me kill you.
阿纳金  我只对共和国制度效忠  忠于民主！
Anakin, my allegiance is to the Republic, to democracy!
如果你的立场和我不同...
If you're not with me...
那你就是我的敌人
then you're my enemy.
只有西斯的思维才这么极端
Only a Sith deals in absolutes.
我得履行职责了
I will do what I must.
你可以试试
You will try.
陛下  我听说你有了个新徒弟
I hear a new apprentice you have, Emperor.
或许应该叫你达斯.西迪厄斯
Or should I call you Darth Sidious?
尤达大师
Master Yoda.
你没死
You survived.
很惊讶么?
Surprised?
傲慢蒙蔽了你  尤达大师
Your arrogance blinds you, Master Yoda.
现在让你领教一下...
Now you will experience...
黑暗原力的全部能量
the full power of the dark side.
我等这一刻已经很久了...
I have waited a long time for this moment...
我的绿色小朋友
my little green friend.
终于  绝地武士终于一个不剩了
At last the Jedi are no more.
只要我还活着就别说大话
Not if anything to say about it I have.
你的统治就要结束了
At an end your rule is.
它已经够长的了
And not short enough it was.
如果你真的那么强大...
If so powerful you are...
干吗要跑呢?
why leave?
你阻止不了我的
You will not stop me.
达斯.维德会比我们俩都要强大
Darth Vader will become more powerful than either of us.
你高估了你的新徒弟
Faith in your new apprentice misplaced may be.
正如你高估了黑暗原力一样
As is your faith in the dark side of the Force.
快点  时间要恰到好处
Hurry. Careful timing we will need.
准备好了就发射你的归航信标
Activate your homing beacon when you're ready.
没找到他的尸体  长官
There's no sign of his body, sir.
- 那么他没死 - 再搜查一次
- Then he is not dead. - Double your search.
好的  长官  马上就去
Yes, sir. Right away, sir.
叫卡基船长去准备我的舰船立即起飞
Tell Captain Kagi to prepare my shuttle for immediate take-off.
- 是的  主人 - 我感觉到维德勋爵有麻烦了
- Yes, Master. - I sense Lord Vader is in danger.
我不能再回来了
Into exile I must go.
我失败了
Failed I have.
我让你失望了  阿纳金
I have failed you, Anakin.
我让你失望了
I have failed you.
我早该知道绝地武士在策反了
I should have known the Jedi were plotting to take over.
阿纳金  帕尔帕廷议长是邪恶的！
Anakin, Chancellor Palpatine is evil!
从我的角度来说  绝地武士才是邪恶的
From my point of view, the Jedi are evil.
那么你的确迷失了！
Then you are lost!
今天是你的末日  我的老师
This is the end for you, my master.
战斗结束了  阿纳金  我占据了高地
It's over, Anakin. I have the high ground.
你低估了我的实力
You underestimate my power.
不要尝试
Don't try it.
你是被选中的那个人！
You were the chosen one!
预言说你会消灭西斯  而不是加入他们！
It was said that you would destroy the Sith, not join them!
给原力以平衡  不是将它领入黑暗！
Bring balance to the Force, not leave it in darkness!
我恨你！
I hate you!
你曾经是我的兄弟  阿纳金
You were my brother, Anakin.
我曾那么关心你
I loved you.
克诺比大师 帕德梅小姐在船上
Master Kenobi. We have Miss Padme on board.
对  请快一点
Yes. Please, please hurry.
我们得离开这可怕的地方
We should leave this dreadful place.
欧比旺
Obi-Wan
阿纳金还好么?
Is Anakin all right?
陛下  走这边
Your Majesty, this way.
他在那儿
There he is.
他还活着
He's still alive.
叫一个医疗舱过来  快
Get a medical capsule immediately.
好的  长官  现在就去
Yes, sir. Right away.
打扰了  尤达大师
Excuse me, Master Yoda.
欧比旺.克诺比和我们联系上了
Obi-Wan Kenobi has made contact.
快把她送医疗中心  快
We'll take her to the medical centre. Quickly.
生理上  她完全健康
Medically, she's completely healthy.
但因为某些未知的原因  我们就要失去她了
For reasons we can't explain, we are losing her.
- 她要死了? - 不知道为什么
- She's dying? - We don't know why.
她失去了生存的意愿
She has lost the will to live.
如果要救宝宝们  我们要马上做手术
We need to operate quickly if we are to save the babies.
宝宝们?
Babies?
是双胞胎
She's carrying twins.
卢克
Luke.
哦  卢克
Oh, Luke.
- 是个女孩 - 莉娅
- It's a girl. - Leia.
欧比旺
Obi-Wan.
他还有良知
There's good in him.
我知道...
I know.
我知道他... 还有...
I know there's... still...
维德勋爵
Lord Vader.
能听见我说话么?
Can you hear me?
能  师傅
Yes, Master.
帕德梅在哪?
Where is Padm?
她安全么?
Is she safe?
她还好么?
Is she all right?
似乎  你一怒之下杀死了她
It seems, in your anger, you killed her.
不会的
I couldn't have.
她还活着  我感觉到了！
She was alive. I felt it!
不！
No!
孩子们必须被藏在一个安全的地方
Hidden, safe the children must be kept.
我们得把他们带去一个
We must take them somewhere where
西斯感觉不到他们存在的地方
the Sith will not sense their presence.
他们应该被分开
Split up they should be.
我和我妻子会抚养这个女孩
My wife and I will take the girl.
我们一直想领养一个女婴
We've always talked of adopting a baby girl.
她会在我们的爱心中成长
She will be loved with us.
那男孩呢?
And what of the boy?
送到塔图音  他的故乡
To Tatooine. To his family send him.
我带他去  我会照看他的
I will take the child and watch over him.
在时机成熟前  我们会暂时消失
Until the time is right, disappear we will.
克诺比大师  等一下
Master Kenobi, wait a moment.
你在塔图音隐居期间  我会指导你的
In your solitude on Tatooine, training I have for you.
指导?
Training?
一个老朋友学会了不朽之术
An old friend has learned the path to immortality.
他从原力的阴间回来了
One who has returned from the netherworld of the Force.
你师傅
Your old master.
奎-刚?
Qui-Gon?
我会教你怎么和他交流
How to commune with him I will teach you.
- 安德列斯船长 - 是的  阁下
- Captain Antilles. - Yes, Your Highness?
我把这些机器人交给你了
I'm placing these droids in your care.
好好照顾他们
Treat them well. Clean them up.
清除他们的记忆
Have the protocol droid's mind wiped.
什么?
What?
哦  不
Oh, no.